<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>World on Galaxy of Thoughts</title>
    <link>/tags/world/</link>
    <description>Recent content in World on Galaxy of Thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright> © Copyright notice</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 02:01:58 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/world/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting Dilemma | Catching Black Swan events</title>
      <link>/post/2020-07-01-forecast_prob/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-07-01-forecast_prob/</guid>
      <description>Week 27 of the year 2020, a year that will be etched in the minds of so many. History will have a place marker for this year. Events have been happening left right and center, throwing the world into a foray of mixed emotions and reactions. From the forests fires in Australia at the beginning of the year taking months to quench out, to the new health crisis of Covid-19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The time for pivotal world change is here</title>
      <link>/post/2020-03-15-world_change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-03-15-world_change/</guid>
      <description>There is a silver lining in every cloud, taking the back seat and analysing situation provides perspective. Lets you peer through different lenses meticulously sifting and searching not leting any thing cloud your judgement. Four months since first cases become globally public in Wuhan China, the spread of the now code named virus COVID-19 continues unabeited. The exponential spread has created a lot of conversation across various forms of media. Some claiming it is being blown out of propotion compared to other virus in the past decade nameing a few Evian flu, Swine flu, SAR, MARS amongst others did not receive such attention.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>