<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Galaxy of Thoughts</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Galaxy of Thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright> © Copyright notice</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Messy affair of DATEing</title>
      <link>/post/2023-10-14-dates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-10-14-dates/</guid>
      <description>Dates are always a messy affairMy apologies if you thought I would be talking about dates, yes definitely I will be talking about dates but not that type of date you thinking but the actual dates.
Do you love dates, personally I do but they can be a mouthful of headaches if you understand what I mean. So here goes my dating scenes.
Planning for datesYou cannot talk about date without specifying time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Been a minute | Am back</title>
      <link>/post/2023-05-21-amback/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-05-21-amback/</guid>
      <description>ME
Since the last time I did any blog update a lot of things have happened it has been almost 3 years now.
Summary update
 Family expanded Started yet another masters, finished course work, stuck on project/thesis Moved countries Changed jobs Moved houses ** and many more things  Am back now though
Watch this space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Youtube Trial Analysis</title>
      <link>/post/2020-10-30-yt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-10-30-yt/</guid>
      <description>Determine what interesting stuff we can deduceTrying to figure out what interesting things I can figure out from the data available. I have been following Mr. Able Mutua’s channel since he started in the beginning of the year.Seemed interesting to start my exploratory discovery of what data has to present us.
Just about snippet description of who Abel is though I know I will outright fail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ningependa kukupa</title>
      <link>/post/2020-10-22-ningependai/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 07:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-10-22-ningependai/</guid>
      <description>Ningependa kukupa Mercedes lakini bado sijapata Bahati
  Ningependa uone ndani ya Audi lakini ni kama Jesus ni wa Kabi, itabidii nimetafuta wangu
  Ningependa tuende holiday ingine more fire but Bonfire hawanijui na Kabu hanitambui na first name basis
  Ningependa tuoneshane mapenzi yetu tele kwa Telly but wacha kwanza tukeep up with the Muraya&amp;rsquo;s
  Ningependa kukupenda kwa matendo na zawadi kama navyo ona wengine wakifanya, lakini kwa sasa hakikisho langu ni kwamba mapenzi niko nayo kwako ni ya thati</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poleni najaribu kujivunia lugha la swahili</title>
      <link>/post/2020-10-21-swahili/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 07:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-10-21-swahili/</guid>
      <description>Nimekuwa mwenye mawazo nyingi sana. Nimekuwa nikiandamwa na zimwi la lugha, jinamizi ambalo limekataa kuniwacha kabisa. Swahili lugha ya kupendeza lugha ambayo najivunia kuongea kila saa na kila mahali. Lakini ikikuja kwa uandishi na kusoma na kitoroka kama ugonjwa, kwa nini?
Tuende pamoja niwaeleze. Kutoka shule ya msingi darasa la kwanza hadi shule ya upili kidato cha nne, yote jumla ya miaka kumi na mbili, Swahili limekuwa somo kama Kifaransa ama lugha nyingine la kigeni.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strangers Thoughts | Poem</title>
      <link>/post/2020-09-18-strangers_thougts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 07:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-09-18-strangers_thougts/</guid>
      <description>A stranger in my mind, a repulsive thought of guilty pleasure. Who is this that is not able to think right, think straight. Excuse me, we might need a straight jacket. The images that are flashing do not seem to be conjured out of the blues. Deep from the interludes of my cranium they seem to sprout out of nothingness of the black hole.
I have seen this before, reminiscing deja vu or confusion of being able to do martial art styles like kung fu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decision Making From Choices</title>
      <link>/post/2020-08-12-choice_decision/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 07:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-08-12-choice_decision/</guid>
      <description>You do not need to know what you want all the time but knowing what you do not want is equally as strong. Our human body adapts accepting new things, food, experiences and environments. Contrarily, when introduced to things it doesn&amp;rsquo;t like the body reacts in worse cases we end up with severe allergic breakouts. Clearly, the body does not know what it wants but definitely it will scream shout even stop if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t like something introduced to the system of the body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Educated - Tara Westover</title>
      <link>/post/2020-07-31-educated/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-07-31-educated/</guid>
      <description>Biography
  Tara memoir through her life, family, religion and education. Being brought up in a extremist Mormon family, I think extremist here is an over kill it is more of survivalist Mormon family. I got to understand Mormon culture, religion and beliefs through her eye lenses.
Reading her experience being raised, with belief of home remedy and herbs to treat all ailments. No hospital or doctors, avoiding government services as much as they could, including school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting Dilemma | Catching Black Swan events</title>
      <link>/post/2020-07-01-forecast_prob/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-07-01-forecast_prob/</guid>
      <description>Week 27 of the year 2020, a year that will be etched in the minds of so many. History will have a place marker for this year. Events have been happening left right and center, throwing the world into a foray of mixed emotions and reactions. From the forests fires in Australia at the beginning of the year taking months to quench out, to the new health crisis of Covid-19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American Dirt - Jeanine Cummins</title>
      <link>/post/2020-06-19-american_dirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-06-19-american_dirt/</guid>
      <description>Fiction
The thought that you can be an immigrant or refugee in a different country never crosses anybody mind. Security privilege you have to be in a country that is peaceful no violence or threat to life be it from wars or natural disasters, is a precious gift.
We never think about this things, until bam it hits you hard out of no where. This is the fate that has befallen many people from different parts of the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>City of Saints &amp; Thieves by Natalie C Anderson</title>
      <link>/post/2020-05-28-city_of_saints/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-05-28-city_of_saints/</guid>
      <description>Fiction
Thrilling fiction of a young girl Tina. Set out to revenge for the murder of her mother, be the justice she feels she deserve. Everything is set and in motion her plan is locked and loaded. The changes she has experienced, the skills she has acquired has posed her as the best riffraff in the Gooondas gang. Her nimble and agile fingers and stature makes entry and exit undetected when undertaking missions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Border Crossing by Pat Barker</title>
      <link>/post/2020-05-18-border_crossing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-05-18-border_crossing/</guid>
      <description>May has been a strenuous month getting to read. Moving from highly interesting and captivating reads in April starting with The New Silk Roads: The Present and Future of the World. I have not done its review but probably won&amp;rsquo;t because I was left in awe of the silk roads, just read it let not reviews tell you otherwise. A whole new understanding of the East will enlighten you.
  It has been a while since my love for history has been aroused this much, the search into the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPESA RECEIPT SERIALIZATION</title>
      <link>/post/2020-05-15-mpesa_receipt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-05-15-mpesa_receipt/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThe main purpose of this particular article if I may call it so about a tweet that popped in my thread a few weeks ago.How the largest mobile service provider in Kenya sequentially labels their innovative mobile money receipts. The receipts are usually in SMS (Short Message Service) format, every transaction you make you receive the SMS with receipt details. Details of amount sent, name, mobile number of recipient and balance of your account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collection of Free online Materials</title>
      <link>/online_links/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/online_links/</guid>
      <description>Collection of online links that I find useful and I need to remember
Though bookmarks work well for browsers but hey I cannot share that to others.
Caveat : Limited to my interest and frequent reads
Disclaimer: Not promotional or marketing of any sorts
R Online BooksR for Data ScienceHappy Git with RAdvanced RMastering Shiny though still under reviewBlog using R once you start road of down, I would advice starting with the RMarkdown which will take you down the rabbit hole to BookdownR CookbookR Graphics CookbookWhat They Forgot to Teach You About RPython Online BooksPython Data Science HandbookCommand line Online BooksData Science at the Command LineOther content/Interesting blog onlineLearn R and Python in Parallel Another Book on Data Science though still under review</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adventure with Kanduyi</title>
      <link>/post/2020-04-28-african_sandle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-04-28-african_sandle/</guid>
      <description>Fiction\Factual
The feeling of soft aerated, oiled and moist feet are quintessential heaven bless for the feet. Being closed up suffocated and squeezed in side closed shoes all day, the relief you get once you remove the pair of closed shoes is non comparable. Though scratching inside your ears to relieve the itchy feeling comes close.
Toddler moments when they get to see their parents after a long day experience it is when untying my shoelace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stay with me - Ayobami Adebayo</title>
      <link>/post/2020-04-20-stay_with_me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-04-20-stay_with_me/</guid>
      <description>Fiction
 I was not sleepy so midnight of 5th April I start reading to push the hours before slumber kicks in. Woe unto me I end up 8 hours later having not have slept but read the book through out the night, loving the story line.
 Setup in the late 80&amp;rsquo;s to 90&amp;rsquo;s Nigeria backdrop, we are introduced to Yejide wife to Akin. Who are the proverbial love at first sight couple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arrow of God by Chinua Achebe</title>
      <link>/post/2020-04-10-arrow_of_god/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-04-10-arrow_of_god/</guid>
      <description>Fiction
The colonialists have been in the region with Ibo people for sometime now. They are setting up government buildings in Ibo land after creating similar structures and head quarters in delta of the Niger river.
The people of Umuonora a collection of six villages which united to from the unprecedented events of that happened a couple of generations ago. Now they have one Chief Priest of Ulu, who is the messenger and has direct communication with the god.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March Reading List</title>
      <link>/post/2020-03-30-march20_reading_list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-03-30-march20_reading_list/</guid>
      <description>The month I found myself starting with a reading list of 11 physical books to read. Clearly my next couple months have been sorted out. I am used to reading while on transit started some while back when my commute to and from work was close to two and half hours, rather than complain and indulge on online chatter profile stalking and all other manner of utter online social media shenanigans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tragedy of commons CovID-19 case</title>
      <link>/post/2020-03-22-tragedy_of_commons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-03-22-tragedy_of_commons/</guid>
      <description>The numerous empty shelves we have witnessed across the various countries in the supermarkets is really a spectacal. At first you would think it is black friday at the start of the year all over. But no the jostling and hustling each other over tissue paper was not because of great offers. On slaught of probable lock down after what we have witnessed in China, might have caused a scare. Neanderthal being in us kicked in, the animal instinct the quick impulisive brain took over, in what Daniel Kahneman book Thinking, Fast and Slow terms as the first system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The time for pivotal world change is here</title>
      <link>/post/2020-03-15-world_change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-03-15-world_change/</guid>
      <description>There is a silver lining in every cloud, taking the back seat and analysing situation provides perspective. Lets you peer through different lenses meticulously sifting and searching not leting any thing cloud your judgement. Four months since first cases become globally public in Wuhan China, the spread of the now code named virus COVID-19 continues unabeited. The exponential spread has created a lot of conversation across various forms of media. Some claiming it is being blown out of propotion compared to other virus in the past decade nameing a few Evian flu, Swine flu, SAR, MARS amongst others did not receive such attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>February Reading List</title>
      <link>/post/2020-02-28-feb20_reading_list/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-02-28-feb20_reading_list/</guid>
      <description>February has been an interesting month, it was the month of the palindrome date 02/20/2020, full blown worry about probable emminent epidemic corona virus named covId-19 among other global phenomena.
My reading list for the month was intriging mainly taking through the journey of discrimination, racism, facism and global geography.
I was able to read 3 books namely:
   No. Book Author     1. To Kill a mocking bird Harper Lee   2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 Jan Reading</title>
      <link>/post/2020-01-30-reading_list/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-01-30-reading_list/</guid>
      <description>on 1/1/2020 started the year with my first book. It had been on my reading list over an year, yes I have a reading list or rather collection of suggested books that I keep track of. My favourite reads have been mainly referrals from previous readers, apart from a few which either I stumble upon and get engrossed into like when I found the book.
  Idling scouring my local bookshop for another title.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beauty of Language</title>
      <link>/post/2019-12-10-beauty-of-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-12-10-beauty-of-language/</guid>
      <description>BEAUTY OF LANGUAGEUnder the tree scenarios play a lot in my mind, questioning and marveling at the interesting facets and crevices of the world. The complex nature of which we find ourselves in, dynamism, mystism, elusions and perfections all sewn into one. One would be forgiven for not appreciating all the asthetics that come from the universe.
Communication is at the core of human societies, cultures and being. The constant longing for expression of self to the universe, seeking attention or addressing a need.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regular Expression Tutorial [Regex]</title>
      <link>/post/2019-04-09-regex_tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-04-09-regex_tutorial/</guid>
      <description>1. IntroductionWhat is Regular Expression a.k.a RegEx , an attempt to define this is at times makes the tool use under explained or overly complicated. Though let me try RegEx in simple terms is a way of handling and manipulating characters in ways different ways while simplifying the effort of the process.
We use RegEx on a daily basis it is just that we do not know areas where we use are below:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>At times when am busy with daily task or basically seated under a tree borrowing from my mentor Isaac Newton, always waiting for something to fall. Hopeful to squeal Eureka.
Am a statistician/data analyst by day and data science enthusiast by night.
 Mental journeys shuttling between utopia, dystopia and bordering paranoia.
 I have been fiddling about the idea of a blog. Nothing fancy just my own space where I pour my thoughts, musings, perturbation and amusements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading Book Collection</title>
      <link>/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/</guid>
      <description>Beeing somewhat an avid reader, I usually get queries on books I can suggest to people for them to read.
So I would recommend and eventually realised most of what I recommend I need to track them. So the simple table below contains titles I have read. Not a comprehensive list though and it has more than enough.
I will try to update as much as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>