<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reading List on Galaxy of Thoughts</title>
    <link>/tags/reading-list/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reading List on Galaxy of Thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright> © Copyright notice</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 02:01:58 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/reading-list/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Educated - Tara Westover</title>
      <link>/post/2020-07-31-educated/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-07-31-educated/</guid>
      <description>Biography
  Tara memoir through her life, family, religion and education. Being brought up in a extremist Mormon family, I think extremist here is an over kill it is more of survivalist Mormon family. I got to understand Mormon culture, religion and beliefs through her eye lenses.
Reading her experience being raised, with belief of home remedy and herbs to treat all ailments. No hospital or doctors, avoiding government services as much as they could, including school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American Dirt - Jeanine Cummins</title>
      <link>/post/2020-06-19-american_dirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-06-19-american_dirt/</guid>
      <description>Fiction
The thought that you can be an immigrant or refugee in a different country never crosses anybody mind. Security privilege you have to be in a country that is peaceful no violence or threat to life be it from wars or natural disasters, is a precious gift.
We never think about this things, until bam it hits you hard out of no where. This is the fate that has befallen many people from different parts of the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>City of Saints &amp; Thieves by Natalie C Anderson</title>
      <link>/post/2020-05-28-city_of_saints/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-05-28-city_of_saints/</guid>
      <description>Fiction
Thrilling fiction of a young girl Tina. Set out to revenge for the murder of her mother, be the justice she feels she deserve. Everything is set and in motion her plan is locked and loaded. The changes she has experienced, the skills she has acquired has posed her as the best riffraff in the Gooondas gang. Her nimble and agile fingers and stature makes entry and exit undetected when undertaking missions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Border Crossing by Pat Barker</title>
      <link>/post/2020-05-18-border_crossing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-05-18-border_crossing/</guid>
      <description>May has been a strenuous month getting to read. Moving from highly interesting and captivating reads in April starting with The New Silk Roads: The Present and Future of the World. I have not done its review but probably won&amp;rsquo;t because I was left in awe of the silk roads, just read it let not reviews tell you otherwise. A whole new understanding of the East will enlighten you.
  It has been a while since my love for history has been aroused this much, the search into the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stay with me - Ayobami Adebayo</title>
      <link>/post/2020-04-20-stay_with_me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-04-20-stay_with_me/</guid>
      <description>Fiction
 I was not sleepy so midnight of 5th April I start reading to push the hours before slumber kicks in. Woe unto me I end up 8 hours later having not have slept but read the book through out the night, loving the story line.
 Setup in the late 80&amp;rsquo;s to 90&amp;rsquo;s Nigeria backdrop, we are introduced to Yejide wife to Akin. Who are the proverbial love at first sight couple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arrow of God by Chinua Achebe</title>
      <link>/post/2020-04-10-arrow_of_god/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-04-10-arrow_of_god/</guid>
      <description>Fiction
The colonialists have been in the region with Ibo people for sometime now. They are setting up government buildings in Ibo land after creating similar structures and head quarters in delta of the Niger river.
The people of Umuonora a collection of six villages which united to from the unprecedented events of that happened a couple of generations ago. Now they have one Chief Priest of Ulu, who is the messenger and has direct communication with the god.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March Reading List</title>
      <link>/post/2020-03-30-march20_reading_list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-03-30-march20_reading_list/</guid>
      <description>The month I found myself starting with a reading list of 11 physical books to read. Clearly my next couple months have been sorted out. I am used to reading while on transit started some while back when my commute to and from work was close to two and half hours, rather than complain and indulge on online chatter profile stalking and all other manner of utter online social media shenanigans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>February Reading List</title>
      <link>/post/2020-02-28-feb20_reading_list/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-02-28-feb20_reading_list/</guid>
      <description>February has been an interesting month, it was the month of the palindrome date 02/20/2020, full blown worry about probable emminent epidemic corona virus named covId-19 among other global phenomena.
My reading list for the month was intriging mainly taking through the journey of discrimination, racism, facism and global geography.
I was able to read 3 books namely:
   No. Book Author     1. To Kill a mocking bird Harper Lee   2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 Jan Reading</title>
      <link>/post/2020-01-30-reading_list/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-01-30-reading_list/</guid>
      <description>on 1/1/2020 started the year with my first book. It had been on my reading list over an year, yes I have a reading list or rather collection of suggested books that I keep track of. My favourite reads have been mainly referrals from previous readers, apart from a few which either I stumble upon and get engrossed into like when I found the book.
  Idling scouring my local bookshop for another title.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>