<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Random on Galaxy of Thoughts</title>
    <link>/tags/random/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Random on Galaxy of Thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright> © Copyright notice</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 02:01:58 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/random/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting Dilemma | Catching Black Swan events</title>
      <link>/post/2020-07-01-forecast_prob/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-07-01-forecast_prob/</guid>
      <description>Week 27 of the year 2020, a year that will be etched in the minds of so many. History will have a place marker for this year. Events have been happening left right and center, throwing the world into a foray of mixed emotions and reactions. From the forests fires in Australia at the beginning of the year taking months to quench out, to the new health crisis of Covid-19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adventure with Kanduyi</title>
      <link>/post/2020-04-28-african_sandle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-04-28-african_sandle/</guid>
      <description>Fiction\Factual
The feeling of soft aerated, oiled and moist feet are quintessential heaven bless for the feet. Being closed up suffocated and squeezed in side closed shoes all day, the relief you get once you remove the pair of closed shoes is non comparable. Though scratching inside your ears to relieve the itchy feeling comes close.
Toddler moments when they get to see their parents after a long day experience it is when untying my shoelace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tragedy of commons CovID-19 case</title>
      <link>/post/2020-03-22-tragedy_of_commons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-03-22-tragedy_of_commons/</guid>
      <description>The numerous empty shelves we have witnessed across the various countries in the supermarkets is really a spectacal. At first you would think it is black friday at the start of the year all over. But no the jostling and hustling each other over tissue paper was not because of great offers. On slaught of probable lock down after what we have witnessed in China, might have caused a scare. Neanderthal being in us kicked in, the animal instinct the quick impulisive brain took over, in what Daniel Kahneman book Thinking, Fast and Slow terms as the first system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The time for pivotal world change is here</title>
      <link>/post/2020-03-15-world_change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-03-15-world_change/</guid>
      <description>There is a silver lining in every cloud, taking the back seat and analysing situation provides perspective. Lets you peer through different lenses meticulously sifting and searching not leting any thing cloud your judgement. Four months since first cases become globally public in Wuhan China, the spread of the now code named virus COVID-19 continues unabeited. The exponential spread has created a lot of conversation across various forms of media. Some claiming it is being blown out of propotion compared to other virus in the past decade nameing a few Evian flu, Swine flu, SAR, MARS amongst others did not receive such attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beauty of Language</title>
      <link>/post/2019-12-10-beauty-of-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-12-10-beauty-of-language/</guid>
      <description>BEAUTY OF LANGUAGEUnder the tree scenarios play a lot in my mind, questioning and marveling at the interesting facets and crevices of the world. The complex nature of which we find ourselves in, dynamism, mystism, elusions and perfections all sewn into one. One would be forgiven for not appreciating all the asthetics that come from the universe.
Communication is at the core of human societies, cultures and being.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>